I'm excited to introduce you to your first exercise, and I'm looking forward to seeing what you make
첫 번째 운동을 소개하게 돼서 기쁘고 어떻게 만드실지 정말 기대되네요
As a reminder, you should have gone to your Anaconda prompt if you're on a PC or your terminal window.
PC나 터미널 창을 사용하신다면 아나콘다 프롬프트를 선택하세요
If you're on a mac, you should have gone to the project root directory.
Mac에 있다면 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리로 가야 해요
LM engineering activated Anaconda by doing conda activate LMS or the virtualenv equivalent if you're
LM 엔지니어링은 LMS 활성화 콘다 또는 그걸 사용한다면 가상env와 동등한 것으로 아나콘다를 활성화합니다 그런 다음 JupyterLab을
using that, and then typed JupyterLab to bring up your Jupyter lab.
입력해 Jupyter 랩을 불러와요
And in the file browser on the left, you should see the weeks like this.
왼쪽 파일 브라우저에 이런 주가 있을 거예요
Or you might be already in the week one folder, in which case it will look something like this.
아니면 이미 첫 주 폴더에 있을 수도 있죠 그런 경우 이런 식으로 되죠
And I now want you to go to the day two exercise notebook, which will come up like this.
이제 둘째 날 운동 공책을 꺼내세요 이렇게 나올 거예요
And here is the plan.
계획은 이래요
What we're going to do is we're going to see how to call a llama from code.
코드에서 llama를 호출하는 방법을 볼 거예요
So we're going to use Python code to call the llama model that's running on your computer.
파이썬 코드를 이용해 llama 모델을 호출할 거예요 여러분 컴퓨터에서 실행되는 거죠
And what we're then going to do and once our first set that up.
그런 다음 할 일은∙∙∙ 첫 번째 설정부터요
So we'll get that to work and you'll be able to see the results.
get get을 하면 결과를 볼 수 있어요
And the exercise for you will be to then update the summarization project that we completed yesterday
여러분이 할 일은 어제 완료한 요약 프로젝트를 업데이트하는 겁니다 그리고 OpenAI
and use Olama use your local model instead of the call to OpenAI.
호출 대신 Olama를 사용해 여러분의 로컬 모델을 사용하세요
And if you didn't sign up for the OpenAI API, then this is your chance to do it for the first time.
OpenAI API에 등록하지 않았다면 이번이 처음 할 기회예요
So, uh, first of all, I explain here that we will be, uh, using a llama.
우선 라마를 쓸 거라고 설명해 드릴게요
The benefits of using a llama, of course, is that there's no API charges.
라마를 사용하면 API 요금이 안 들어요
It's open source.
오픈 소스 소스예요
It's running on your box.
당신 박스에서 작동해요
It's free.
공짜예요
Another benefit is that the data will never leave your box.
또 다른 장점은 데이터가 상자 밖으로 나가지 않는다는 거죠
So if you're ever working on something, whether it's confidential data that absolutely must not go
여러분이 뭔가 작업하고 있다면 그게 클라우드로 절대 가면 안 되는
to the cloud, then of course this gives you techniques to be working locally without data leaving the
기밀 데이터든 간에 이건 인터넷에서 데이터가 떠나지 않고 로컬에서 작업할 수 있는 기술을 제공하죠
Uh, the disadvantage is that, uh, obviously the frontier models, they are many, many times larger
단점은 개척자 모델은 오픈 소스 모델보다 훨씬 크고 강력하다는
and more powerful than the open source models.
거예요
And so we should expect that the results won't be as strong.
그러니 결과가 그렇게 강하지 않을 거라고 예상해야 해요
But, you know, that's what you pay for when you pay your, uh, your, your, uh, fraction of a cent
하지만 한 통당 1센트도 안 되는 돈을 냈으니 당연한
each call.
거죠
First of all, a recap that you hopefully already installed Olama by going to Olama.
먼저 올라마에 가서 올라마를 설치한 걸 복습해보죠
Com and you remember, it's just a matter of pressing that download button and you're off to the races.
기억하세요 다운로드 버튼만 누르면 바로 레이스가 시작되죠
If you've done that, then if you visit this link here localhost 11434, then you should see this Olama
그걸 완료했다면 여기 localhost 11434 링크를 방문하면 이 올라마가 실행 중인 메시지를 볼 수 있습니다
is running message which tells you that it's running.
실행 중이라는 걸 알려주는 거죠
If that doesn't show, then bring up a terminal or a PowerShell and just enter Olama serve and it should
안 나오면 터미널이나 PowerShell을 불러와 OlamaService를 입력하면 실행될
then be running.
거예요
And if you go there, you should see again a llama is running.
거기 가면 라마가 뛰는 걸 볼 수 있어요
So with that, if that doesn't happen then then try and do a little bit of debugging and research and
만약 비트가 작동하지 않는다면 디버깅과 조사를 해보시고 저에게 연락하세요
then contact me and I'll help all right.
제가 도와드릴게요
So I'm going to do a few imports.
몇 가지 일을 할 거예요
Now I'm going to set some constants.
이제 상수를 설정할게요
This here is a URL on my local box on this port which is you see the port that runs on slash API slash
이건 제 로컬 상자 이 포트의 URL이에요 슬래시 API 슬래시 채팅에서 실행되는 포트가 보이시죠
I'm going to have also a constant called model which will be llama 3.2.
모델이라 불리는 상수도 가질 거예요 그게 라마 3이 되겠죠 2번요
Now this here this messages, uh, hopefully you will recognize this construct because this is the same
여기 이 메시지들은 여러분이 이 구조를 알아보셨으면 합니다 메시지와
construct as the messages.
같은 구조니까요
Let me lay it out a bit differently for you.
비트를 좀 다르게 표현해 볼게요
This is the same as the messages that we talked about before.
전에 얘기했던 메시지와 같은 거예요
Uh, that we use with OpenAI.
오픈라이에 쓰는 거예요
Messages is a list of dictionaries, the dictionaries.
메시지는 사전 목록이에요 사전들요
Each dictionary has a key of role, and the value is either user or system and a key of content, and
각 사전은 역할의 키를 갖고 있고 그 값은 사용자나 시스템 그리고 콘텐츠의 키입니다 그 값은
the value is the user message or the system message.
사용자 메시지나 시스템 메시지죠
So this very simply is saying I want to have a user prompt that says, describe some of the business
간단히 말하자면 사용자 프롬프트가 이런 말을 하는 거죠 인공지능이 재생되는 일부 비즈니스
applications of generative AI.
응용 프로그램을 묘사하라
Let's run that.
실행해 보죠
I'm now going to put that into a JSON object called a payload, which specifies the model, the messages,
이제 그걸 페이로드라는 JSON 객체에 넣을 거예요 모델과 메시지를 지정하는 거죠 결과를
and I don't want it to stream results.
스트림하지 않고요
I just want to get back the results.
Get it 결과만 받으면 돼요
And I'm then going to use the Python package requests to post that request to this URL pass in the JSON.
파이썬 패키지 요청을 이용해 JSON 내의 이 URL 패스 게시할 거예요
And then what I get back, I'm going to take the JSON look in the message content fields, and we'll
그런 다음 JSON을 메시지 콘텐츠 필드에서 살펴보겠습니다 호출을 하면
see what happens when we make that call.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
So right now of course it's making web requests locally from my box to my box.
지금은 제 상자에서 제 상자까지 로컬로 웹 요청을 하고 있어요
And it's connecting to the llama 3.2 model that's being served by llama.
라마 3에 연결되고 있어요 라마가 제공하는 2가지 모델이죠
And this is the result.
이게 그 결과예요
And I will tell you that the answers that it gives are really good.
그 결과는 정말 훌륭하다고 장담해요
So that since we are trying to learn about commercial applications, it would do you no harm to read
상업적 응용 프로그램에 대해 알고자 하는 거니까 일부 응답을
through some of its responses and see if there's anything that interests you.
읽어보고 관심 있는 게 있는지 보세요
Now, I wanted to show you that because I wanted to explain exactly what's going on behind the covers
이걸 보여드린 건 뒤에서 무슨 일이 벌어지는지 설명하고
and that we're making these basically these URL, these web requests to our local box.
싶어서예요 이런 URL 즉, 로컬 상자에 대한 웹 요청을 만들고 있죠
But in fact, the friendly people at Allama have built a Python package, which makes this even simpler.
하지만 사실 알라마의 친절한 분들이 파이썬 패키지를 개발해 주셔서 작업이 더 간단해졌어요
So you can just do this in one line.
한 줄로 하면 돼요
So I could have started with this, but I wanted to show you the steps to making the web request so
이걸로 시작할 수도 있지만 웹 요청을 만드는 단계를 보여드릴게요 실제 무슨 일이
you have a good intuition for what's actually happening.
일어나는지 직관적으로 알 수 있게요
But there is this nice package, Allama, that you can just import, and then you can say Allama dot
Allama라는 멋진 패키지가 있어요 그냥 가져오면 되죠 Allama.챗이라고
chat, pass in the model, pass in the messages, and then just take back the response content.
입력하고 모델 통과, 메시지 통과 그리고 응답 콘텐츠를 가져오면 돼요
And if I run that, we should hopefully see that we will get basically the same thing.
그걸 실행하면 기본적으로 같은 게 나오죠 get
And here we go.
자, 보세요
There it is.
저기 있네요
Uh, and I imagine yeah, I can Uh, already see that there are differences between them.
그리고 제 생각엔 네, 벌써 차이가 있다는 걸 알겠어요
Of course, it's somewhat unique each time.
물론 매번 독특하죠
Uh, this one looks like a longer response.
이건 좀 긴 것 같네요
Okay, that's the end of my teeing up.
티업은 다 했어요
Now it's over to you.
이제 당신에게 달렸어요
So you'll remember in day one, we built this solution that where we built something that would summarize
첫날 이 솔루션을 구축한 걸 기억하실 겁니다 웹사이트를 요약하는 뭔가를 구축했죠
a website, and we made a call to OpenAI to achieve that.
그걸 달성하기 위해 OpenAI에 호출했어요
Here, in fact is our call to OpenAI right here.
사실 오픈AI를 호출한 건 여기죠
The challenge for you is to keep going with this day two exercise lab and add in that same summarizer
여러분이 하실 일은 이 2일 차 운동 랩을 계속하면서 동일한 요약기 코드를 추가하는 겁니다
code so that you can build a website, summarizer, that uses your local Ulama open source model, llama
그래야 Ulama 오픈 소스 모델인 llama 3을 사용하는 웹사이트를 만들
3.2 or a different model if you wish to do your summarization.
수 있으니까요 요약하고 싶다면 다른 모델을 사용하세요
That's the exercise.
그게 연습이죠
The solution is in the solutions folder should you need it.
솔루션은 솔루션 폴더에 있어요 필요하면 쓰세요
But I think you've got this one and I will see you for the next video when you have that done.
하지만 이건 된 것 같네요 다음 영상에서 다시 뵙죠